scubaboard.com 2008-12-16

# ScubaBoard - Privacy Policy

|  **Register today and make this ad disappear!**  
|  Welcome to **ScubaBoard** , an online scuba diving forum community where you can join over 100,000 divers from around the world discussing all things related to Scuba Diving. To gain full access to ScubaBoard you must register for a **free** account. As a registered member you will be able to: 

  * Participate in over 500 dive topic forums and browse from over 3,000,000 posts.
  * Communicate privately with other divers from around the world.
  * Post your own photos or view from 80,000 user submitted images.
  * Gain access to our free classifieds marketplace to buy, sell and trade gear, travel and services.
  * Use the calendar to organize your events and enroll in other members' events.

All this and much more is available to you absolutely free when you register for an account, so sign up today! 

If you have any problems with the registration process or your account login, please contact the ScubaBoard Support Team.  
  
---|---  

### Privacy Statement for ScubaBoard

ScubaBoard.com has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for this web site: ScubaBoard. 

### Information Automatically Logged

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers and to administer our web site. Additionally sections of our site related to voting / ranking use an IP address for non-demographical reasons to prevent multiple fraudulent voting. 

### Cookies

Our site uses cookies to make sure you don't see the same ad repeatedly. We also use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, and to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site. You may notice things like forum systems show your username when you enter. This is done with cookies. We also use cookies to show if content has changed since your last visit to that site, or area of a site. 

### Advertisers

We use an outside ad company to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our web site, cookies received with banner ads are collected by our ad company, and we do not have access to this information. Some customer data is shared with the advertising companies. This information is limited to broad demographical information and does not include cookie related tracking information or personal user details. Demographics and cookies are not tied to personal user information. 

### Registration & Contest Forms

ScubaBoard may collect data on users via registration forms, contest forms and survey forms on our site in which we ask visitors for general contact information (like an email address), unique identifiers (like a customer ID), and demographic information (like zip code, age, or income level). Contact information from the contests is used to ship purchases, information about our company, and to send promotional material from some of our partners to our customers. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary, and to share with other companies who may want to contact our visitors. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice / opt-out section below. Financial information that is collected is used for classification, profiling, and traffic analysis purposes. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. This information may be shared with advertisers on an aggregate basis. We use this data to tailor our visitor's experience at our site showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences. 

### External Links

This site contains links to other sites. ScubaBoard is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. 

### Special Relationships

  1. Google AdSense provides advertising content for ScubaBoard, and collects data and other information from our sites. You may view the Google AdSense Privacy policy at [www.Google.com/AdSense](http://www.google.com/adsense). 
  2. vBulletin is a software provider of ScubaBoard. No user information is exchanged in this relationship. 
  3. PhotoPost is a software provider of ScubaBoard. No user information is exchanged in this relationship. 

### Public Forums

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and / or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. Our forums require the collection of personal information (including but not limited to name, email address, location, and IP address). This information is used solely to insure any users violating our content rules can be contacted. 

### Children's Guidelines

We care about children and understand that they have special privacy needs. Therefore, we have adopted the following privacy policy regarding children: 

  * We will **not** collect, use, or distribute to third parties personally identifiable information without prior verifiable parental consent. 
  * We will **not** give the child access to unmonitored chat rooms, message boards, email accounts, or other services that would give the child the ability to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable information without prior verifiable parental consent. When verifiable parental consent is not obtained, we will only use the online contact information (such as email) to: 
    * Respond directly to the child's request on a one-time basis and not use that information to re-contact the child for other purposes. 
    * Request the name or online contact information of a parent for the purpose of obtaining verifiable parental consent or providing parental notification. 
    * Respond more than once directly to a specific request from a child (such as in the case where a child requests a newsletter subscription) and not use this contact information to re-contact the child for other purposes. We will use our best efforts to provide parental notification, which will include the nature and intended use as well as an opportunity for the parent to prevent the use of the information and participation in the activity. 
  * We will **not** entice the child to divulge more information than is needed to participate in any activity, game, or service. 
  * We will provide the parent a description of the specific types of a personally identifiable information collected from their child upon request. We will allow the parent to refuse further use or future online collection of personally identifiable information and provide a way for a parent to obtain any personally identifiable information collected from their child. 
  * We will provide notice to children in age appropriate terms of what personally identifiable information is to be collected. 
  * We will **not** provide any links to web sites that are unsuitable for children. 
  * We will encourage children to get their parents' permission before sharing personal information online. 

### Choice / Opt-Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving promotional / marketing information from our partners, and us. 

  1. All forms of media have an opt-out method - some have URL's or specified pages that you can opt-out through, others may have an e-mail address to reply to with instructions on how to opt-out. In all cases, you can e-mail the ScubaBoard Support Team at [support@scubaboard.com](mailto:support@scubaboard.com) and we will gladly assist you to ensure your time with us isn't frustrating. 
  2. NOTE: All services have their own features to opt-out of any publications. 

### Data Quality / Access

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided: 

  1. You can send email to [support@scubaboard.com](mailto:support@scubaboard.com). 
  2. Each service will have its own feature for users to change / edit their personal information.
